What does a superhero have to do with
teach my students the
feelings and emotions of level
Hello Hispanics and welcome
once again to Spanish with Vicente in the
Today's lesson we are going to learn the
vocabulary related to the
feelings and emotions and why
This topic is very simple because once
You have all asked me more and
you with almost 40 percent of
40% of you had never voted for the votes
a topic with so much consensus among everyone
you guys so today we're going to talk
of the vocabulary of feelings and
emotions and that's what I'm going to do
To do is what we call in Spain to kill
two birds with one stone this expression
You know the truth And why do I say this well?
because many times you have asked me
series recommendations for example
to learn Spanish and today what I'm going to do
to do is that I'm going to talk to you about one
series of a series where there are superheroes
and at the same time I will teach you
Spanish vocabulary related
from this video So today we're going to
Learn Spanish with the series El vecino
you are ready and prepared to go ahead
[Music]
Well, what is this series about?
Why this series is a good series
Netflix original Why The Chosen One
Well, I've simply decided.
because Netflix is the platform of
world's largest streaming service
moment therefore it is easier than
many of you have access to
watch this series is also original
Netflix which means it's going to
always be in the Netflix catalog
and also well of course I have it
chosen because it is a Spanish series and
because I'm watching it right now
I also have to say it but I have
started watching it to show you this
vocabulary that is included I don't usually see
series well Let's talk about this series of
What is this series about? Well, as already
You will have seen in the thumbnail of this
lesson this series is about a superhero
but a normal, ordinary superhero
Well, of course not. No, not really.
could be a normal superhero and
current is basically a guy who
overnight it turns into
superhero thanks to some pills
magical Well I have to say I don't know
They have really messed up their heads with the script.
ordinary guy who takes a
pill and becomes a superhero
They have really broken their heads, the truth is
to prepare the script But well I
I am here to teach you Spanish and to
talk about this series and so what
we are going to do is we are going to talk about
the four characters of the series here
You have Javier and Lola who are the
protagonists now José Ramón now Julia
how good are the protagonists not
we can say that only actors
secondary no And as in all series
of the world Each character is different
So I'm going to start by talking about Javier.
the protagonist Who is this guy this
uncle is a uncle from my point of view
very honest sincerely in the first
chapters it seemed to me that although
He seems like a person who maybe doesn't
controls his impulses but deep down
I think he is a super honest person.
a person who seems to be very
aligned with its values and is a
person who is very honest with his/her
acts and the truth is that although I did not have
a bad life but I think that since
He is a superhero because he feels very good
It is true that he has taken a liking to
This superhero life And that makes me
to think that in his previous life well in
his previous life Well before having
superpowers Well he was a little bit
even the hat was a bit like
We say in Spain up to the crown or
up to his neck in life He worked in
a bar had a normal life and
ordinary as any other citizen
Here you have another normal expression and
ordinary or like any son of a bitch
neighbor Well what I mean is that
Well, I had a life like you or me
like any ordinary person with a
I work as a couple etc. etc.
But I think I was fed up with it.
because since she has powers, well,
The truth is that the kid feels
but I don't know the feeling that it is
feels much happier
with his new life and I also have to
say that he is a very constant person
He doesn't break down easily, things happen to him.
good and bad things but when you
Bad things happen, he's a guy who doesn't know
collapses, it doesn't come down, you know
stay And the truth in this life is
important when bad things happen to you
So don't break down, don't give up
and the protagonist Well the truth is that
It doesn't come down well Let's talk about
The other protagonist in this case is
Lola the actress is called Clara Lago both
the protagonist you saw before
who is the actor Kim Gutierrez if not me
I'm wrong. Well, I'll look into it, but I do think so.
that Skim Gutierrez and this girl are two
well-known actors in Spain and this
girl who in the series is called Lola
I sincerely believe that it is the only one
person in the series who really has
two fingers in front, it seems to me that it is the
the only one that has two fingers on its forehead
because the protagonist sometimes with the
superpowers because he goes a little crazy
Because sometimes with so much energy and so many
powers become like a motorcycle and well
Well, sometimes he does things he shouldn't.
How to throw Well I'm not going to do it for you
explain why I'm going to ruin it for you
end but what I was telling you
It seems that this girl is the only one who
He has two fingers on his forehead, it seems to me.
is the only person who
reasons things very well before
do them and always think about the
consequences so positive point
for our very important protagonist
He also cannot stand injustices
also like Javier is a
very honest person but has a
small defect we can say and it is that
If you watch the series you will see him.
hooked on social media is
She's hooked to her cell phone all the time
with the mobile looking at his followers
when you're hooked on the networks
social that can generate a problem
of addiction but Well This is the only one
negative point is a girl who has
two fingers on the forehead and it's a person
the following one is also quite complete
character is José Ramón and the truth is
which is my favorite It is my favorite because
the protagonist has superpowers
Well, sometimes he does some things that he doesn't
I would have to do it but this guy
sincerely he doesn't lose his temper
things in the series and the guy to see
Obviously, well, sometimes it gets a
a little nervous but And such But but no
It climbs the walls, I think it is
a rather calm person and not
loses his temper, he also knows how to maintain
His emotions It is true that he is a
character who doesn't have many
features or anything but well it's a
uncle who as my grandmother would say is a heaven
or a sun this expression is very common in
Spanish to be a sun or to be a sky I the
truth is I wouldn't use this expression OK But
My grandmother, for example, does use it and
what to say this very simple when
We say that someone is a heaven as much as a
man as a woman means that he is
very good person that this person has
very good heart Ok Normally you can
say it is also a sun Ok a sun or a
solete in a slightly affectionate way no
but when someone is a sun like that
says a sun to be a sun both for
men as for women Well
Basically what we mean is that
He is a very good person with very good
heart and this boy José Ramón because the
true Hey, he is a person of Forgiveness
sorry what I wanted to say is that this
boy is a sun is a pleasure of person and
Finally we have Julia, a girl who
The truth is also very honest.
He seems like a very honest person and also
It is a personal pleasure especially because
It happens to him like it happens to me, he gets very angry
Bad people make you very angry
some people do bad things
acts not as it can be I know then
like never before, someone who parks
in a disabled parking space and she, well
He reproaches him, it doesn't give him much courage that
people do this kind of things
Well, it seems like something quite a lot to me.
coherent no and is one of the
co-protagonists who at the
throughout the series because they charge a lot
importance and although it has therefore
gets more responsibilities
throughout the series because he is a person
that is not overwhelmed, is not felt
overwhelmed when they come to her
responsibilities are held firm well
And now it's your turn Which of these
four characters you liked the most And
why Or if you know any other
character from your superhero series or
from your favorite superhero movie
So tell me what this character is like in the
comments and, while we're at it, practice
with the vocabulary of this lesson And
Well since we're talking about this
The Neighbor series if you want to learn which one
is the difference between our
superhero the neighbor and homelander of the
Voice series Well, on the way to the
c1 of the online Spanish academy you
I explain what is the difference between
These two superheroes to see in reality
The goal is to learn Spanish but
Well you already know me too if
you want to see what it looks like
Commander Tamayo from the series The House of
paper and Spiderman you have to do this
lesson you're seeing right here
on the way to C1 around here
up I'm going to leave you a button in case you
You want to register with the Spanish Academy
online And well then in this lesson
Let's talk specifically about similarities
and differences between some of our
favorite superheroes and villains
Basically what you're going to do is
learn Spanish and well that has been it
Everything in this lesson tell me in the
comments How is it or What
characteristics does it have? What profile does it have?
your superhero or your
favorite superhero Tell me here
see if you practice with something that
We have seen in this lesson and well then
That's all I hope as always that
you have learned a lot of vocabulary
and see you in the next lesson until
then
[Music]